Good morning.
Morning.
Mezato-san. G-Good morning.
Why didn't you come to our
meeting spot yesterday?
Oh... Morning, Mob-kun.
Sorry about our plans yesterday...
I totally forgot about them.
You forgot...?
The brass had a meeting
the day before the gathering.
And that's when he appeared...
--The true founder.
--Huh?
I'm sorry I dragged you into this when
you were clearly the wrong person.
Don't worry about it anymore.
Don't worry about what anymore?
"Ishikawa Naoko" "Kageyama Shigeo"
Wait, what's going on?
MOB MOB WOW! MOB MOB WOW!
I realized that my youth was grey
The root of this irritation is unknown
My brain runs parallel with this emotional train
Struggling adolescence
Don't disturb the subconscious mind
Who's that behind me?
Opposing ideas, distortion
Purge the sorrow
So, do what you can now.
My life
Finally
Break it down!!
(WANT) desire (YOUNG) and sincerity
(BURN) they begin to sprout (1) within my chest
(TRANCE) I won't awaken (CHANCE) but I want to
(STANCE) both sides of the coin
(1) are back-to-back
Accept me as I am
Conflicting freedom and relations
If they can become one
That smile will be
One and only "1"
MOB MOB WOW! MOB MOB WOW!
"Mob Psycho 100 III"
MOB MOB WOW!
One and only "1"
"Mob Psycho 100 III"
"Mob Psycho 100 "
MOB MOB WOW! MOB MOB WOW!
One and only "1"
"Divine Tree 1
- The Founder Appears~"
"Body Improvement Club"
Sorry, I totally forgot.
I have no idea why I
suddenly forgot, though.
Does it have something to do
with the Psycho Helmet Religion?
Huh? How did you know?
Some members approached me yesterday
and invited me to some seminar,
and I ended up way more interested
in that than the universe.
Boys, starting today, this room is
no longer for the Telepathy Club,
but the Salt MS branch of
the Psycho Helmet Religion.
What?
What the heck are we supposed to do?
We will pray to the Psycho Helmet Religion!
Apparently, you'll be blessed
if you do it five minutes a day.
That's random as hell.
"Hideaway Café"
"Spirits and Such Consultation Office"
"Hideaway Café" "Spirits and Such Consultation Office" So
the gathering for the Psycho Helmet Religion yesterday...
So the gathering for the Psycho
Helmet Religion yesterday...
That video has over two million views.
Well? That's the guy who became the founder.
Does he look familiar?
No, not at all.
He is a psychic, right?
After that display, everyone there fell in line.
If this guy's gonna be the founder,
sadly, I don't think
they'll need you anymore.
Well, whatever.
You were never the type anyway.
So what's this important thing
you wanted to talk about?
Oh, yeah...
Pictures of buildings?
Wow, those cracks are intense...
Buildings deteriorating due to
some supernatural phenomena.
I went to have a look up close,
and it wasn't due to faulty construction.
The cause was plant roots.
Thinking back, I guess that one building
had already been affected, too.
The roots across the city
are busting through reinforced steel
and concrete to scour for nutrients.
I thought it might be some exotic plant,
but the source of the roots
was the worst possible place.
The culprit is the most popular thing
in the city right now...
It's the Divine Tree.
The broccoli?
Yup! Meaning if we let that thing
continue to run wild,
all we'll ever get are those jobs
asking us to investigate buildings.
Is that really a problem?
It's a lot of work, and worse,
it doesn't bring in any money.
Not to mention, we are slightly
responsible for that thing, too.
Mob... I need your help.
We're going to go destroy that broccoli!
All right.
Hello! Please take one.
Uh... What is this?
"The Divine Tree's Bounty"
It's a powder made from
part of the Divine Tree.
Think of it as a nutritional tonic.
They have a new menu item!
I want the Divine Tree parfait!
They have Divine Tree croquettes, too!
You can even sample stuff!
Seasoning City sure is putting a lot
of effort into bringing tourists in.
What's that?
Divine Tree candy, I guess.
--Is it good?
--What's it taste like?
Hey!
Oh, homemade cookies?
"I sprinkled some Divine Tree powder
on them, which increases vitality,
so please eat them and feel better."
I guess they were handing out this
powder in front of the station, too.
Yup, it's totally normal.
I'm sure the powder just
has a placebo effect.
"Milk" I'm sure the powder
just has a placebo effect.
I'm sure the powder just
has a placebo effect.
This is great...
The Divine Tree... is amazing.
Psycho Helmet-sama... Huzzah.
Powerful brainwashing that totally
takes over your emotions...
This is what they're
handing out in the city?
They won't get away with this.
Now I'm mad!
The source of the brainwashing seems
to be coming from the Divine Tree.
I'm gonna destroy it
and get it out of this city!
Must be past here.
Sorry, but I'm gonna open up a hole.
A barrier?
I guess you were expecting me.
Wait. Is that you, Kageyama-kun?
I guess he just looks like him.
Who are you? What are you doing here?
Who am I? I'm...
...God, of course.
God? God... Of course.
I beg your pardon, Psycho Helmet-sama.
Please forgive me.
Look what you did to the Divine Tree
that empowers my existence...
I'll let this slide for today. Now go home.
Thank you very much.
Carry on being faithful.
Yes. Faith. God. Psycho Helmet.
Divine Tree. Religion...
Empty?
Tch. Man, you're a pain in the ass, too.
How dare you!
How dare you brainwash
me not once but twice!
It's not brainwashing. This is a blessing.
For those who have nothing
and long for a place to belong,
I'm giving them exactly that.
Come on, now. Are you trying to kill me?
Well, you're not a person, are you?
Correct.
I am God!
You're a bit off your rocker
if you're going to defy God.
Go on! Just think about it!
He's trying his brainwashing again...
That's enough!
Your brainwashing signal...
...forcefully makes people venerate
the Psycho Helmet Religion.
But strong emotions can fight it
and overcome the brainwashing.
Here I come.
I've had enough of all of you fools
trying to control people through power.
That won't help make you God...
...nor will it make you... the star.
Now, then. I wonder who you actually were.
What's this?
Minegishi-kun, you can take your break now.
Thank you...
--Sir.
--What is it?
There seems to be something
wrong with the plants.
These flowers were fine this morning,
but now they're wilted.
It's as if they've had
the life sucked out of them.
-- I think we should find out the cause--
--Minegishi-kun.
I told you you're on break,
so take your break already.
"Smiley Flowers"
Who knew that having
a proper job was so rough?
Even weeds on the side
of the road are weakened.
And the crack is bigger than yesterday.
What's causing this?
What tree are you from?
I see.
The Divine Tree.
It's stealing the energy
from all of the plants in the city.
If this is left unchecked,
the land will start to die.
I'm glad I realized this early on.
"Tea
You grew far too greedily.
This is an order. Do not--
"Let's be respectful "Let's make sure
to take any dog poop home with us"
"Let's be respectful” "Let's make sure to take any dog poop home with
us” Hey, Minegishi-kun. How long of a break do you plan on taking?
"Let's be respectful "Let's make sure
to take any dog poop home with us"
"Let's be respectful” "Let's make sure to take
any dog poop home with us"” Huh? Minegishi-kun?
Huh? Minegishi-kun?
"Tea
Impossible...
You sure are persistent. How long
are you gonna keep regenerating?
You won't be able to stop me.
Will you, Hanazawa?
I see.
I guess you really were
just a worthless evil spirit.
So what's with that appearance, Dimple-kun?
I used the stems of the Divine Tree
to create a body
and designed it with the icon of
the Psycho Helmet Religion in mind.
Because the believers wouldn't be able
to see me if I remained a spirit.
What are you after?
Does Kageyama-kun know
you're flying off the handle like this?
Shigeo doesn't matter.
I've only ever had one goal.
And that's to become a modern God.
I see. That's a shame. I never thought
I'd have to eliminate you again.
I'll just tell Kageyama-kun
that you quietly passed on.
This is goodbye!
"Psycho Helmet Religion" "Seeking Part-timers!!"
"18 and over~"
Doesn't something seem weird?
Hm?
The whole city.
It feels like we're being watched.
You mentioned that you thought
you were finally becoming popular.
Everyone goes through a stage
of feeling overconfident, but...
I wouldn't go around talking about it.
Because you're going to
regret it in a few years.
You said you wanted to destroy that broccoli.
What did you have in mind?
Well, I have actually thought it through.
Simple, right?
"1. Lift it up with psychic powers."
"2. Carry it off." Simple, right?
"2. Carry it off."
"1. Lift it up with psychic powers."” "2. Carry it off."
Um... So I'm the one who's going to carry it to the ocean...
"1. Lift it up with psychic powers."
"2. Carry it off."
"1. Lift it up with psychic powers."” "2. Carry it off."
Yup. I'm going to secure routes and guide you there.
Yup. I'm going to secure routes
and guide you there.
"3. Sink it into the ocean." Yup. I'm
going to secure routes and guide you there.
"3. Sink it into the ocean."
This is gonna be a lot of work.
It'd be great if we can
find someone to help.
Well, Serizawa's at school...
How about your brother?
Ritsu... He had a student
council meeting today,
so he might still be at school.
--Ritsu!
--Heya.
Uh...
I'm pretty sure it's impossible
to lift that thing, Nii-san.
A while back, a few of us carried a piano.
It would've been impossible alone,
but we could do it together.
So maybe we can do this, too.
Here is powder from the Divine Tree.
Here you go. It's great for your health.
What's the matter?
Do you wanna bail after all?
--Er...
--Come on, Ritsu-kun!
If we don't do something, we won't be
able to live in Seasoning City anymore!
My mom said that when she planted
watermelons in her yard,
it killed off all of the
other plants and flowers.
Just look at the size of it!
It's probably sucking all life out of the soil.
Okay, okay. I got it. I'll help you out.
Is something wrong?
No, it's probably nothing.
Prayer time?
What do you mean by that?
We're going to offer a prayer
so we can have another blessed day.
What are you talking about?
Are you feeling all right, Makihara?
What would we be praying to anyway?
We'll be praying to Psycho Helmet-sama,
who embodies the Divine Tree.
All in favor, say aye.
Hey, Makihara--
Aye.
Wait! This is insane.
--Quit fooling--
--Now, now.
No reason to decline so hastily.
It is always difficult
to accept new opinions.
Kamuro?!
Nii-san, have you heard of
the Psycho Helmet Religion?
Huh? Are you interested in it, too, Ritsu?
No way. But there are a lot of believers
at our school, apparently...
And the rate at which
it's spreading is bizarre.
And their object of worship, or whatever...
...is that Divine Tree, apparently.
Hm... Meaning if we destroy the broccoli,
we'll be making enemies of those people.
But everything I've looked up about them
suggests they're pretty harmless.
They sell merch and hold discussions.
It seems more like a fan club
rather than a religion.
It's like a gathering where they all obsess
over something unusual, pretty much.
And you'd usually call that strange.
Of course, we should be on our guard.
They might even try
to get in our way. Hm...
Let's just go with pulling it out quickly
and get the hell out of Dodge.
My head hurts!
I'll have some sugar.
Ritsu, you took some candy to school?
Oh, this? I got it from the student
council president earlier.
Kageyama-kun, before you go home, here.
What are these?
Apparently, it's a candy being made
to lure tourists to the city.
But my father got a bunch of samples
at the prefectural assembly.
Sure, thanks.
You're a lifesaver.
Have one, Nii-san.
Thanks.
You, too, Reigen-san.
Oh? Er, I'll take one for later.
I'll have mine later, too.
After I pull out that broccoli.
Could we make a pit stop on our way there?
He sure is walking fast.
Where are you going, Ritsu?
Ritsu?
"Seasoning City Civic Center"
"Seasoning City Civic Center" In here. There
are some people I want to introduce you to.
In here. There are some people
I want to introduce you to.
This is the civic center.
Ritsu, who are these people?
They're members of the
Psycho Helmet Religion.
Huh?
Nii-san, let's rethink this.
R-Rethink what...?
You can't play dumb with us.
You're trying to destroy the Divine Tree?
The Divine Tree brings peace
to everyone's hearts.
We need the Divine Tree in our city.
Hang on a sec...
When did you start leaking
information to these guys?
Ritsu, what's wrong?
I just suddenly realized that I need
to protect the Divine Tree.
And then I just had a feeling
that everyone would gather here.
What are you planning to do,
bringing us here?
That candy!
Have a seat, Nii-san. You, too, Reigen-san.
Here you go. Have some tea, too.
No need to be so guarded.
Let's talk this over peacefully.
How about it?
I guess they're not even willing to listen.
I don't think we needed to run that fast...
If we stayed there,
we would've fell under some group
hypnosis and ended up believers.
Take out your candy, right now!
My candy?
That place had a bunch of these.
This might be how Ritsu got brainwashed.
Ritsu got brainwashed?
I can't leave him like that.
Calm down!
He doesn't seem to be in any real danger yet,
so we need to carefully look into--
Hey, there...
Resistance is futile.
Psycho Helmet-sama sees all.
Mob, I think you're right.
We're definitely being watched.
Huh? What the hell is that shirt?
Why did you take off your jacket?
I got hot after we ran.
Keep it on. Your school jacket
has higher defense points.
Trying to do something
about the Divine Tree?
But that's impossible.
Reigen Arataka.
--Gah!
--I heard that you were plotting to cut down the Divine Tree!
--I heard that you were plotting
to cut down the Divine Tree!
I'm going to lecture you and--
Ah! He ran away!
Damn it!
Looks like most of the people in the city
have become Psycho Helmet Religion believers.
How did this happen? How can we...
Psycho Helmet is an unknown psychic.
I have no idea what he's thinking,
let alone what his endgame is.
I'm sure he'll try to interfere
if we go to the Divine Tree.
If he's some kind of villain, let's free
everyone from their brainwashing,
even if it means taking him down.
Say, Mob.
What do you think about
the Psycho Helmet Religion?
Do you think they're bad guys?
No. I don't think they're bad people.
They were just having fun
doing something as a group.
You think so, too? I also--
But things are different since
their new founder appeared.
"We are looking for our God.
Psycho Helmet Religion”
"We are looking for our God. Psycho Helmet Religion" If that
person is a fake and is fooling everyone into worshiping them,
"We are looking for our God.
Psycho Helmet Religion”
"We are looking for our God. Psycho Helmet
Religion” I don't like how they're doing things.
I don't like how they're doing things.
But, Mob...
There never was a true founder,
so how can you call him a fake?
Huh?
Are you trying to say that
you're the true Psycho Helmet?
No...
The founder's existence was based
on a false image to begin with.
I don't actually think
Psycho Helmet's a bad guy.
Every community needs a leader.
It's natural to think of him
as the president of a club.
I'm sure he's mostly just responsible
for figuring out their group activities
and making sure everything runs smoothly.
I'm sure it's a tough job.
He's pulling off something
you're not capable of doing.
You don't need to hold a grudge
against him or anything.
In the end, the one who
has the most fun wins.
Maybe it's not a good idea to take
their Divine Tree away from them
if they need it so badly.
All right. Let's head home, Mob.
Master Reigen... This is just a hunch...
...but have you been brainwashed?
Me?
Well... I see.
So this is what it feels like to be accused
of being brainwashed when you're not.
The hearts of the citizens are
far more important than the city.
Most of the people in the city are
believers of the Psycho Helmet Religion.
We should just respect that.
From now on, this city--this world--
Is going to live in harmony with the Divine Tree
and the Psycho Helmet Religion...
Hey, Mob! I'm not going!
Hey!
Even when I close my eyes, this ache
lingers Hey, Mob! I'm not going! Hey!
Even when I close my eyes, this ache lingers
If I'm just mistaken, that'd be great.
If I'm just mistaken,
that'd be great.
The shade burns so much it's almost
lost If I'm just mistaken, that'd be great.
The shade burns so much it's almost lost
But that person, and that person,
and that person, and that person...
As we reluctantly part in our last moments
Colored in navy blue, this hand reaches
for the missing piece
for the missing piece It could be...
Colored in navy blue, this hand reaches
for the missing piece
Colored in navy blue, this hand reaches for the missing
piece ...that I'm the only one left in this city...
Colored in navy blue, this hand reaches
for the missing piece
(Sign) Not lying to the point of bragging,
the truth that isn't safe
(Chain) I suddenly realized that I was protected
and that you were close by
(Chain) I suddenly realized that I was protected and
that you were close by Are you going to see them?
(Chain) I suddenly realized that I was protected
and that you were close by
(Chain) I suddenly realized that I was
protected and that you were close by Yes.
Yes.
(Pain) As I adorn this armor of ambition,
this friendship is only partially visible Yes.
this friendship is only partially visible
(Pain) As I adorn this armor of ambition, this friendship is only
partially visible ]I want to meet with them and talk to them directly.
(Pain) As I adorn this armor of ambition,
this friendship is only partially visible
(Pain) As I adorn this armor of ambition, this friendship
is only partially visible Oh? Everyone, make way.
Oh? Everyone, make way.
(Remain) It's all right, I knew that
from the start Oh? Everyone, make way.
(Remain) It's all right,
I knew that from the start
(Remain) It's all right, I knew that
from the start Mob-kun is coming through.
(Remain) It's all right,
I knew that from the start
(Exist...Exist...)
I can hear the voice of Psycho Helmet-sama...
Whoa, yes... you're not alone
Whoa, yes... you're not alone Kageyama
Shigeo is the original Psycho Helmet-sama!
Whoa, yes... you're not alone
Amazing!
Whoa, yes... you're not alone The
original Psycho Helmet-sama has returned!
The original Psycho
Helmet-sama has returned!
Whoa, just... accept that The original
Psycho Helmet-sama has returned!
Whoa, just... accept that
There are two Psycho Helmet-samas!
We have two founders now!
Whoa, just... accept that
Hooray!
Things are getting even better!
Whoa, just... accept that
Whoa, just... accept that --Psycho Helmet! Psycho Helmet! Psycho Helmet...!
--How wonderful...
--Psycho Helmet! Psycho Helmet! Psycho Helmet...!
I adore you so much!
English Translator: Michelle Tymon Translation Editor: Zachary
Carlysle Translation Checker: Sriram Gurunathan |I adore you so much!
English Translator: Michelle Tymon Translation Editor:
Zachary Carlysle Translation Checker: Sriram Gurunathan
Hey, calm down, Mob.
Are you sure you should be
defeating Psycho Helmet-sama?
Seriously, though. You should reconsider.
Next time on Mob Psycho 100 Il Episode 5:
"Divine Tree 2
- Peace~."
Illegal downloads?
Do you want to be cursed?
"Divine Tree 2 - Peace~" illegal
downloads? Do you want to be cursed?